Whenever you’re talking to people, say what you have to say. But once they start replying
Bất cứ khi nào nói chuyện với ai đó, hãy nói những điều bạn phải nói. Nhưng khi họ bắt đầu phản hồi lại bạn,
back to you, completely ignore it. It can’t possibly be interesting or important. In fact,
hãy lờ đi. Chẳng có gì thú vị hay quan trọng đâu.
it is critical that you use this time to prepare for what you’re going to say once they’re
Thực ra, bạn cần sử dụng khoảng thời gian này để chuẩn bị những phải nói khi họ nói xong.
done. Think very hard about what absolutely genius thing you’re going to say next. Also,
Nghĩ thật kĩ về những điều tuyệt vời bạn sẽ nói tiếp sau đó.
make it really obvious that this is exactly what you’re doing by not showing any form
Ngoài ra, hãy thể hiện rõ rằng đó là những gì bạn đang làm bằng cách không chen ngang
of acknowledgement once they’re done and if you can, start your next thought even if
khi mà họ đang nói và nếu có thể hãy bắt đầu những suy nghĩ tiếp theo của mình
they’re not quite finished with their final sentence.
ngay cả khi họ còn chưa dứt lời
Whenever you’re around people, complain a lot. If you’re meeting someone after work
Bất cứ khi nào ở cạnh ai đó, hãy than phiền nhiều vào. Nếu bạn chuẩn bị gặp ai sau giờ làm
for dinner, make sure you tell them all about how horrible it is to work where you work.
để ăn tối, hãy chắc chắn rằng bạn sẽ kể lể với họ làm việc ở cơ quan bạn thì tồi tệ thế nào
If you can, also throw in some unpleasent facts about your family for extra bonus points.
Nếu có thể, hãy đưa ra vài dẫn chứng không dễ chịu về gia đình để tăng tính thuyết phục
It’s not enough that you’re drained after a long day of work, you can’t possibly be
Một mình bạn mệt mỏi sau một ngày dài làm việc là chưa đủ
happy until the other person is completely drained as well.
bạn sẽ chẳng thể nào vui nếu người kia cũng không mệt như bạn
The following step works well with anyone, but I’ve found that it works especially
Bước tiếp theo có hiệu quả với bất cứ ai, nhưng tôi phát hiện ra nó đặc biệt hiệu quả
well if you have a significant other. Like most people, she probably has great qualities
cao nếu bạn một người đặc biệt. Giống như bao người khác, cô ấy có lẽ có những
along with some unpleasent ones. And you know very well which ones you need to focus on.
phẩm chất tốt và vài khuyết điểm. Và bạn biết rất rõ bạn nên tập trung vào điểm nào
Don’t ever say anything appreciative about how she cleaned up your mess, or how she tried
Đừng bao giờ nói những lời cảm kích cô ấy đã thu dọn mớ hỗn độn của bạn thế nào,
to make you happy yesterday... These things are irrelevant. Focus instead on the one negative
hôm qua cô ấy làm bạn vui ra sao... Những thứ đó không liên quan. Hãy tập trung vào một điểm
trait she has and constantly criticize her for it.
tiêu cực và liên tục chỉ trích cô ấy
Always walk around with a pissed off and an unpleasent face. Don’t ever smile. When
Luôn đi xung quanh với bộ mặt cau có khó chịu. Đừng cười.
people don’t react well to you and your social interactions suffer, be confused as
Khi người ta không phản ứng tốt với bạn và những tương tác xã hội khác chịu đựng,
to why...
hãy bối rối hỏi tại sao...
Make sure to not make any effort to remember people’s names. It’s not like you can
Hãy chắc chắn bạn không cố gắng ghi nhớ tên người khác.
make them feel like you care if you do. If this task requires that you put in extra effort
Làm thế không có nghĩa bạn có thể khiến họ thấy bạn quan tâm.  Nếu việc này đòi hỏi
or figure out a way to get better at this, come up with an excuse to not take responsibility.
quá nhiều nỗ lực và bạn cần ghi nhớ tốt hơn, hãy đưa ra một lí do biện hộ
One that works really well is the following... All you have to do is say this magic sentence:
Có một lí do khá hiệu quả. Bạn chỉ cần nói câu thần chú:
“Sorry, but I’m not good with names.” This somehow completely takes away any need
"Xin lỗi, mình không giỏi nhớ tên lắm". Bằng cách nào đó, câu nói này sẽ phủi bay
to make an effort, and hey, now you’re the victim. Congratulations!
bất cứ yêu cầu nỗ lực nào, và này, bạn là nạn nhân đấy. Chúc mừng!
Remember at all times that the most important person is you, and therefore the most important
Luôn luôn nhớ rằng bạn là người quan trọng nhất, và vì vậy,
interests and hobbies in the world are of course the ones that you have. Don’t ever
mối quan tâm và sở thích quan trọng nhất trên thế giới dĩ nhiên là cái bạn đang có.
genuinely be interested in what’s going on with other people. Your one friend’s
Đừng quá thành thật mà quan tâm chuyện của người khác.
a martial artist while the other’s a soccer player? Don’t ever ask them what that’s
Bạn có một người bạn là võ sư còn người kia là cầu thủ bóng đá? Đừng bao giờ hỏi họ cảm thấy như thế nào
like and possibly look at things from a new perspective. No, those are barbaric and unsophisticated
rồi nghĩ rằng có thể nhìn mọi vật từ thế giới quan của họ. Không, đó là những thói quen man rợ nhưng đơn giản
practices you have no interest in. Instead always talk about reading books and how that
mà bạn chẳng hề thích thú. Thay vào đó, hãy nói về việc đọc sách và
is the most important thing in the world. And while you’re doing that, make sure to
tại sao nó lại trở thành việc quan trọng nhất trên thế giới này. Và khi bạn thực hiện điều đó, hãy chắc rằng
tell them about how much you love Dale Carnegie as well.
bạn đã kể cho họ biết bạn yêu Dale Carnegie đến nhường nào.
Don’t ever make people feel important especially when you’re dealing with people in a position
Đừng bao giờ khiến người khác thấy họ quan trọng nhất là khi bạn đang đối mặt
of power. If a cop pulls you over, don’t ever say things like “yes, sir” or “yes,
với người quyền cao chức trọng. Nếu cảnh sát bắt bạn tấp vào lề, đừng nói những điều như "Vâng, thưa ông", "vâng, thưa bà"
ma’am.” Talk to him or her like you talk to your homeboys. After all, you are a self-proclaimed
Nói chuyện với người cảnh sát ấy như bạn nói chuyện với người quen. Sau cùng, bạn là "gangster" tự phong
gangster and any other form of interaction would be a weakness on your part. As a result,
và bất kì hình thức tương tác nào khác sẽ trở thành điểm yếu của bạn.
end up with a ticket that is ten times worse than what you would have gotten by making
Do đó, cuối cùng bạn nhận được cái mác xấu xa hơn gấp mười lần so với những điều đáng lẽ bạn đáng nhận được sau khi khiến người khác cảm thấy rằng họ quan trọng. Ý tôi là nó chẳng giống việc những người quyền lực
the person feel important. I mean it’s not like many people in a position of power aren’t
the person feel important. I mean it’s not like many people in a position of power aren’t
strictly there just because they get that sinister sense of pleasure from other people
không gặp phải trường hợp này chỉ vì họ cảm nhận có điều gì đó không ổn khi học làm người khác thấy vui
making them feel important.
bằng cách khiến họ cảm thấy họ quan trọng.
Whenever it becomes really obvious to you and everyone around you that you are wrong,
Bất cứ khi nào nó trở nên rõ ràng với bạn và mọi người xung quanh là bạn đã sai rồi.
do not admit it. To you, that is a sign of weakness and it will embarass you. Don’t
Đừng thừa nhận. Đối với bạn, đó là điểm yếu và nó sẽ khiến bạn cảm thấy xấu hổ. Đừng
say something respectable like, “You guys are right. I had a wrong perspective on this.
nói bất cứ điều gì đáng kính chẳng hạn như, "Này anh bạn đúng rồi đó. Tôi đã nghĩ sai về nó.
Thanks for teaching me something new.” No! Don’t do that! That will actually get rid
Cảm ơn vì đã dạy tôi điều gì đó mới mẻ nhé." Không! Đừng làm thế! Điều đó thật sự
of any possible embarassment and make people respect you.
sẽ xóa đi mọi sự xấu hổ và khiến mọi người tôn trọng bạn hơn.
And finally, work hard at cultivating the inability to put yourself into another person’s
Và cuối cùng, hãy nỗ lực để ngăn chặn cảm giác đặt mình vào tình huống của người khác,
shoes, always think about only what you want, and never appeal to the interests of the person
hãy luôn chỉ nghĩ về điều bạn muốn, và đừng bao giờ cảm thấy hấp dẫn bởi sở thích của người mà
you’re dealing with. If you work at a business and you want to ask for a raise, walk in there
bạn đang trò chuyện cùng. Nếu bạn đang làm trong công ty và bạn muốn được tăng lương, hãy bước vào phòng
with a mindset of how you think you obviously deserve more, and how you want to be able
with a mindset of how you think you obviously deserve more, and how you want to be able
to afford more things, and how you should get a raise just because you’ve been there
to afford more things, and how you should get a raise just because you’ve been there
a certain amount of time... Don’t mention or show how your work is critical to moving
a certain amount of time... Don’t mention or show how your work is critical to moving
the business forward cause let’s be honest, it’s probably not. Plus, then you’d be
the business forward cause let’s be honest, it’s probably not. Plus, then you’d be
appealing to the business owner’s interest and that might actually get you a raise. But
appealing to the business owner’s interest and that might actually get you a raise. But
hey, don’t do that... These types of thoughts don’t occur to you. The ability to put yourself
hey, don’t do that... These types of thoughts don’t occur to you. The ability to put yourself
in another person’s shoes, think about what they want, appeal to their interests, and
in another person’s shoes, think about what they want, appeal to their interests, and
therefore maximize the chances of getting what you want is alien to you.
therefore maximize the chances of getting what you want is alien to you.